Ejiroghene Laurel DAFE

Nigeria | dafelaurele@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn | Blog | (+234) 0803 895 2793

CAREER SUMMARY

A Cloud DevOps Engineer with hands-on knowledge of architecting, automating and optimizing deployments over cloud infrastructures. Proficient with infrastructures as code, configuration management, and continuous code monitoring. Possess a strong team spirit with experience in client-facing positions and keen about the energy and the drive that is obtainable in learning and working with cloud tools and technologies.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Linux System Administration
- Containerization (Docker)
- Infrastructure and Configuration Management (Ansible, Terraform)
- Basic Understanding of Programming languages (HTML, CSS, Javascript, C, Python, PHP)
- Scripting (Bash, YAML, HashiCorp Language)
- Cloud Providers (AWS, GCP, Azure, Digital Ocean, Linode)
- Virtualization (Vagrant)
- Research tools (Google, Stack-Overflow, Github Issues)

Soft Skills

- Customer-focused
- Relationship Management
- Technical Writing
- Business Development
- Leadership
- Tenacity

- Analytical and Logical Thinking
- Teamwork and building
- Quality Assurance
- Effective Communication
- Highly Adjustable
- Research

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

- Containerized and deployed a Laravel application on Digital Ocean using Docker, reducing overhead and minimizing resources used by a good percentage.
- <u>Automated and configured Infrastructure on Amazon Web Services using Terraform and Ansible speeding up infrastructure provisioning time by 80%.</u>
- Defined a highly available and secure Infrastructure on AWS to host a web app on an Nginx server using Ansible, Amazon EC2, ALB, Auto-Scaling groups, Route 53,SSL and VPC
- Built and deployed a static website using Amazon Web Service S3 and CloudFront
- Deployed and hosted a highly available Laravel application using Ansible, Apache2 web server, Amazon EC2, MYSOL, Route 53, SSL and VPC.
- Created fun terminal games using Bash-Scripting, increasing Scripting skill by 50%.
- Developed a redact app as a team project using HTML CSS and JavaScript, improving existing skill of teamwork and building by 30%
- Programmed a Tip calculator app using Python
- Designed a portfolio website using HTML and CSS

EDUCATION

Alt-School Africa

In view

Graduated: October 2012

Diploma, Software Engineering

Delta State University, Abraka

Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy

Organizations/Awards: 2nd Best Graduating Student

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Solutions Architect Associate

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

British Computer Society, Certificate in Information

Technology

In view Achieved May 2022 Achieved August 2021

WORK EXPERIENCE

Open Source Community Africa, Abuja

Core Team Volunteer

• Plan and host Open source events physically and virtually, increasing open source contributions in the community.

Conaj Concierge Limited, Abuja January 2022 – August 2022

Cloud Engineer Intern

• Utilized Terraform and Ansible for automated infrastructure provisioning on AWS which reduced manual provisioning by 60%.

Laurel Cakes And Pastries, Abuja December 2018 - December 2022

Sole Proprietor

- Worked with over 100 clients to understand business requirements and develop effective improvement and assurance strategies.
- Business Development Identify business leads, pitch to new clients, and maintain relationships with existing customers; Increasing returns by 70%.
- Managed Social Media Pages and Created Content increasing sales drive by 65%.

May-Brands Limited, Abuja

January 2015 - November 2017

Assistant Business Manager

- Assisted the Business manager in all aspects of store operations to ensure that customers and business expectations are met and exceeded within the business strategy, thereby increasing store productivity by 50%.
- Improved sales growth up 45% by ensuring proper visual merchandising of products available, to stimulate interest and entice customers to make purchases; identified stock issues, executed planned advertising and promotions.
- Recorded 80% store target accomplishment during work period by training and overseeing the development of over 10 Sales Trainees in the region.

January 2023 - present

- Modified Terraform files to provision infrastructure on AWS, including EKS clusters, EC2 instances, IAM roles, VPCs, and S3 buckets.
- Employed Version Control practices to manage code base, increasing code monitoring and version management by over 70%.